

# Rafi Rasheed T C

Student, Intern at MakerGram

## Rafi Rasheed T C

Peredath House, Mundmuhzi Vazhakkad(PO), Malappuram Kerala, India -673640

+91 9747165032 / +91 7907348448 mail@rafirasheed.co

#### **About**

I'm an engineering student in CUSAT who is passionate about technology and science. I'm an experienced Arduino developer and good in hardware product design, PCB design, IoT and Python. Currently, I'm working as an intern in MakerGram. Also, I worked several freelance projects in the field of firmware development.

## **Experience**

#### MakerGram / - Intern

01/2020 - Present, Remote

Remote internship in MakerGram. MakerGram is a community for makers, innovators, and engineers.

for more details: makergram.com/community/user/rafitc99

#### **Calicut university** / Hardware developer - Intern

06/2019 - 07/2019, Calicut

Developed a voltage protection system for a 3phase circuit at the University of Calicut.

## **Education**

### GHSS Vazhakkad /HIGH SCHOOL

2005 - 2015 -, Vazhakkad

I completed my schooling here.

#### **GHSS Vazhakkad** / Higher Secondary

2015 - 2017 Vazhakkad.

Completed My Higher Secondary education. Specialized in 'Computer science' under 'Kerala Board of education'.

# **CUCEK / Undergraduate.**

2018 - 2022 - Present, Alappuzha

Pursuing my Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication under COCHIN UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY(CUSAT).

## Skills

- Arduino Developing.
- PCB designing.
- Python.
- C/C++
- Micropython
- Project Management
- IoT
- ESP8266 SDK
- RTOS

# Languages.

- Malayalam
- Native
- English
- Intermediate

# Community

- Hackster.io Kerala
- GDG Cochin
- GDG Kozhikode
- Programmer Me -President
- TinkerHub -campus lead
- School Of AI Calicut
- OpenHack IoT
- Hack Club -campus lead
- MakerGram
- HackClub

# Projects.

#### Barish.

Arduino based Rain prediction system.

This project was done in *MakeATon* hackathon held in CUSAT. Created by my team named *Regression*. The project was a local weather prediction system using IoT.

#### Android Arduino RC Car.

Arduino based RC car.

This project was my science fair project. BlueTooth controlled Arduino

rover with real-time video monitoring with temperature, fire, gas monitoring, and detection.

# Water level monitoring.

Arduino water level monitor.

A water level monitoring system for Home. It shows live monitoring of water in the tank and automatically ON/OFF motor if the water is under/over the level.

#### Farm bot.

Telegram based farm bot

Arduino controlled farmhouse which can control and monitor via telegram.

## 3 phase voltage protection.

Over/under voltage protection

Digital voltage protection system for 3 phase circuits.

## Temperature monitoring.

Arduino based IoT project

Real-time temperature monitoring and push data into Samsung Artik cloud.

## **Social**



rafitc



rafitc



rafirasheed\_



rafirasheed\_



rafirasheed.co



**Rafitc**